to fix the world Friday bitly will be
joining me shortly I don't really know
what to say until he gets here
update update I'll update him anyway um
which is why wait to see if anyone else
joins comes on board it's been an
amazing week
and I really wanted to sound check with
the Bentley as well because I have a
different setup because the microphone
sound on this was annoying me when I
would listen to the recordings so I
don't know how that was sounding for
anyone else and whether this is better
it seems to be better when I use it for
the iPad videos that I'm doing which is
what I guess I can't update on yes I've
been working on a video series to
explain the tech cooperative and it's
funny because I feel like I can't
explain the whole big picture in a
single elevator pitch and yet writing
out the basically like the chapters and
no Bend mate yeah well audio okay yeah
is my audio okay I was a changed set up
so I didn't know if it sounds okay
alright I think this is a slightly
better mic than my other one and hoping
this doesn't brush against it it's one
of the positives being deaf in one ear
could only wear one help things and I
yeah it still blocks out everything else
so alright I put a few items on the
agenda but mainly I guess we just start
kind of like with your Toro with we both
you had said that you were gonna look at
existing tech for unimportant yeah and
then I'd said I was gonna contact the
web designer and get an update and just
like do my five conversations this week
since episode was the first weeks I
think what I said I was trying to listen
to it last night in like a very chaotic
community environment with kids playing
on the piano I was like how did that go
which part the tech the tech
and stuff yeah okay so I looked around I
did not see anything that was extremely
helpful for our needs an existing tech I
mean you could do similar what you did
before we could put out a doodle and
then have everyone kind of put in their
times that they're available and then
you can look for like columns that have
groups of four people and then kind of
but someone has to still do that kind of
consolidation and matching up there
doesn't be seem to be a system that will
match a mini to mini group of more than
four people into groups of four or
anything ROI similar to that and it
didn't seem to be any benefit to using
any of the tools that are out there so I
think that kind of means that if we want
something for this we'll have to
actually develop it my thought on that
is it's actually fairly complex
integrating with calendar api's which
may not have to be in v1 but anything to
do with dates and times is very tricky
so I think what we need to talk about is
how do we want to fund or find a
volunteer to build this I'm not going to
have development time until middle of
next year or something because I'm
working on other projects and my day job
is pretty busy so we we might need to
find either volunteer or find some way
to funding fund it so we could pay a
developer yeah absolutely I mean those
are the two options someone does it for
free or and or we pay someone I mean
there's always kind of be in between
option if someone's willing to do it for
way cheaper because it's for a bigger a
bigger mission but yeah people
especially if it's not a two-hour
project and it's tens dozens hundreds of
hours it definitely needs to be a paid
position I think unless I went up there
is both Ian wants to sit around work you
know on something like this um
there's of course always the possibility
crowd funding it the issue with any of
that stuff is just there's two of us
right so if and even though I've been
online it sound like I have tens of
thousands of people that these things go
towards there's a piece of like that's
why I was doing it on YouTube is because
it's free and it's usable enough but
especially is something I have on the
agenda that I wanted to talk about about
this being such a powerful tool for
introverts and yet introverts aren't
even gonna know they want it until they
try it and they're definitely not going
to want to try it on YouTube I think and
so finding the way to fund it is huge we
kind of and that's where like the idea
that I had because I'm very risk-averse
is always looking for like the number of
people who can put in a little bit of
money as opposed to getting one person
to put in a bunch right which is what
crowdfunding is the issue also is making
a professional crowdfunding campaign
right making it so that people want to
put in their money explaining what the
the mission is and what so maybe that's
what we want to focus on because the
worst that happens is it we make one and
we learn from it right and it's a it's a
failure but we learn from it and we know
when you release a new one and even if
it brings some people on board to be
here to launch the next round of funding
campaign don't bring some people on
board who are willing to do like even
someone honestly in the game bSpace
might be working on something that's
similar right
Janelle it's not like I the amount of
time she's like well I'll just try
something and see if it works there are
people that have that type of
personality and have the possibility
capacity to be doing little things like
that but it has to speak to them it has
to be something that they want to spend
time on and are capable of doing and so
yeah both of those things that we can
work we can use this space and work on a
crowdfunding campaign and or we can also
use this space to build our viewership
talking about that so that there are
more people to both crowd fund
crowdsource which is even bigger of like
people who hey my cousin might be
willing to do this for like I don't even
know I don't understand the complexity
of the text so I don't know how many
hours slash how much money it would cost
to create this is it in the hundreds of
thousands
is it a couple thousand like what is the
so I would say five to ten ten to us
yeah that's a pretty generic ballpark
figure for any sort of app with moderate
complexity yeah so I mean we've I think
the final concept of together tech was
to have people donating five to ten
dollars a month we could also just start
that and then when there's enough funds
available have someone start working on
it if we could if people would
understand the idea well enough to start
donating to it or without having an
actual product like you know we talked
about it'd be nice to have the first
together tech technology and then people
would feel value immediately from paying
for it but we can also just do a patreon
or something similar to that that if
we're able to get the vision and other
people catch it then you know that it
could it could grow and in that way yeah
absolutely and I am working on within my
capacity the ability to like I'm doing a
video series I want to have it ready for
December first and then the idea is
however many videos there are they it
launches one a day and to explain a bit
of what it is the bigger vision is for
for together tech and why we want I mean
the first four and then I tweeted about
it earlier was like oh yeah like tech is
powerful right the big four have a lot
of power in our society tech is risky
doing this right like we need five to
ten thousand dollars to make a little
thing and we don't know if it's going to
be successful but together tech is more
powerful and less risky and that in and
of itself is the essence of what we're
doing like to create a
thing that it doesn't mean they're zero
risk like we are taking the risk of time
out of our week because we can you see
the bigger vision at least pieces of it
and the more we're able to get other
people to see that that I think there is
an absolute need for this like people
are ready for something that's going to
give them hope for the future and they
can see that's a very simple message
like yeah I get the tech is powerful I
get the test cos risky if you have any
kind of business issue or sorry business
background or can understand that and
then the the piece of like together it's
more powerful because we own it together
and we're spreading up the risk and
there is like it's a different incentive
decreed it right we're not creating it
so that you and I can become
millionaires down the road we're
creating it so that millions of people
can come on board and improve their
lives and if we make some money out of
that great but that's not the like
founding ideology right creating the
less risk part is that less for the
financial risk the people are more
willing to put in their labor whether
that's um emotional mental physical
labor or something that they own
together that they can see is going to
give them something back because other
people are gonna put in their labor and
they're gonna get to be rewarded with
that and so that is what I'm working on
is creating that and it's just like each
chapter each one of those four I just
said in stone five minute video and then
a bunch of other videos of like okay
well here's here's what we can create
together right both the foundational
piece of together tech like idea cafe
and the time management the finding a
group the fruit management and just that
we can build on all of those things
right create the beta version and then
just continually improve them and once
we have those five to ten tech tools
that hopefully are integrated into one
then the sky's the limit then we can
create everything the history one the
science one you know the food one that
grows your own like helps you coordinate
with your neighbor and grow food in your
backyard like basically if someone can
think it up if somebody has a problem
there's a way to work through with a
group of people there's a way to not
come
with Omega and all utopian solution but
a solution that people can come on board
for and there's enough people to make
that viable so that we're starting with
like one issue how do we one issue how
do we get our politics in line whatever
the issue is we're starting with one and
then I'm figuring it out for that any of
that makes sense where was I going too
many directions at once
no that'll make sense I think those
videos are a great idea that's part
about moving you know getting people
aware of it getting people interested in
it or giving me the opportunity to be
interested so but I think what we need
to do is as a way to capture that
interest so we talked previously about
having a landing page and an email
capture form and at least so I think
that's pretty high in the list and then
I think it would be good to also list
out in kind of bullet port for more
short descriptions some of our ideas for
the different tech then we think fits
well we might find and then maybe have a
survey of some sort we might find that
there is a different tack other than
idea cafe that just gets more traction
and we may then choose based on that
data to start with that one so yeah so
that that would be my proposal as the
next priority is to get a landing page
up and maybe a survey in which we're
already kind of working on the landing
page and stuff with it together tech
website so yeah it's not within my
capacity to do a landing page but if the
person working on it is able to do that
in the next week or so that would be
great she didn't really give me a
timeline as far as when it's getting
done I mean she's a mom and figuring
that out and then with health challenges
as well from what I understand and so I
don't know did she contact you very good
I did not see it in email this morning
at 3 a.m.
sorry I haven't checked is that's that
but yeah we'll see when she gets around
to on the double check real quick
because the other thing is like the I
what I'm doing for the video with a
video see
it's gonna be its own playlist on
YouTube but also just a Google Doc that
I don't have the capacity to make into a
landing page but once it is just a
Google Doc it has just hyperlinks to the
different videos and maybe another page
that is the the top dozen projects right
there like six that are together tech
like the thing we need to build together
tech together right and the maybe six
most powerful ones that are about us
living better lives and connecting more
as a society and what we can build off
of that and then I don't have the mic I
don't know how to do the email capture
or make the landing page but I imagine
that's fairly easy to transfer that into
yeah yeah once it's there the WordPress
site and I have like I know what it
won't the WordPress site together Tech
org and so I don't know whether it makes
sense for me to connect with her and ask
kind of like actual timeline when this
is gonna get done and possibly just
using together tech org for just a
landing page in the meantime or like I
don't have those two things coordinate
together yeah I would just feel her out
or if she contacts me I can kind of feel
out for whether she feel comfortable
with either me or just start focusing on
just a quick landing page and then flush
everything else out yeah
but of course she's donating her time so
yeah I think whatever she's comfortable
with but I think it's worth kind of
suggesting that or and and see what she
thinks
okay okay so yeah the issue is like
she's not creating a website from
scratch she's transferring over like
she's taking what I had created on Wix
for free and making it WordPress so that
it's SEO searchable and there's an email
so you know like you can capture the
email form in the contacts and
everything so I don't know if she's even
looking to do something like that right
that it would necessarily make sense for
the landing page itself but what I don't
know is if it's possible to put up a
simple landing page for now well the
other part is being put up and I don't
think so because that's the part she's
working on right is the part of like she
has a somewhat working prototype on her
computer and it's moving it over to get
together teknorg and making that work
and that's the part that seems to be
like falling apart so having a landing
page there while she's doing that
probably doesn't work it's mine
there there's there are ways to do it I
just don't want to complicate her if
she's in a learning process
unnecessarily complicated so you
wouldn't've reach out I can chat and see
kind of what which process flow she's
doing and then I could make some
recommendations on like yeah there's
just several ways to do it but it does
add it's not a whole bunch of complexity
but if someone's new it might it might
be confusing yeah yeah and we could also
I mean if we wanted to kind of get
started no I don't have time I was gonna
suggest I create a landing page just on
my own website and gain some interest
then could later redirect it but I was
think I have time to do that before she
would so you know always wanting to do
more than we really have time to do
right yeah I wish I had because I have
the time but I don't have the capacity
to learn new skills and but like I can
utilize what I already know in the time
that I have and so like if I'd already
learned tech skills before brain damage
if I only am a time machine that
would've been great but I don't and so
working within the best of our our
capacity and her kabocha and that is
part of what we're doing is figuring out
like what works for us as individuals to
be able to create a technology company
together and own it together
and a big piece of it is stuff needs to
get done who is doing it what's the
timeline and who has the capacity and
the time and the knowledge all at the
same time yeah
and I think continuing to do the game B
idea Cafe and some other things will
still kind of expand people's awareness
of of what it is and what we're doing so
I think all those efforts and of course
your video work and just having these
live I think all is still building
pretty well so yeah yeah that was also I
didn't actually put it on the agenda but
what we're doing in the idea Cafe for
game be right next week's question is
why why do we want game B and I think
part of like the agenda or we can
discuss here is that why piece right
like why why idea Cafe like what is the
thing behind it that is the like burning
thing that society needs that we think
of that like you know what I mean in
that you feel what is the why am I why
because I think that speaks to more
people than the how you know like here's
how we're technically doing it we need
to do the how that is the board meeting
right it's like the moving it forward
but the why piece is more oh yeah I do
want that to be something and offering a
like YouTube is great because it's
within my capacity but it's not within a
lot of our death our potential guests
capacity like they don't want to be live
on YouTube right and so doing it in a
way where it's private is fine but even
then they're like but it's on their
right doing zoom calls which can be
dozens of people and then broken up into
groups is feasible but then it's picking
a timeslot picking in order to be in the
same time every week and that's right
like I'm not gonna do that on zoom'
until the idea cafe for game B is big
enough that there's people watching it
and there's people who want to
participate in cat consistently but but
doing like game be such a small group of
people compared to Twitter or Facebook
that having something like the game be
idea cafe this speaks to me at least if
I'm the one hosting it and the world and
that was kinda what the idea cafe was in
the beginning it was like hey let's just
pick a topic for anything um like you
know we talked about 9/11 we talked
about donor donation our donor
conception and especially the mental
health
and those like I on it like I don't know
how to showcase how powerful it is
because I don't think the audience gets
it the only way is to actually
experience it and be like oh this is way
better than tweeting at each other this
is way better than or maybe it's not I
don't know what was your experience with
the idea cafe on I think it was good I
definitely liked learning audio rather
than text I although I do prefer
structured so some of the other tools
that have been developing I'd almost
prefer to use that but but this is a
necessary step before we use those tools
because you need to have a you need to
have a kind of a brainstorming a time to
generate new ideas and then and
understanding the why and stuff like
that so I found it useful so yeah okay
ask what you mean by structure like what
what what are other people offering that
is structured more structure that is
useful well no one's offering anything
more structured but the tools I'm
building are so yeah actually break it
down into yeah because you know if you
have five minutes you're saying some 250
statements and you have all these
different threads kind of going off and
no one can remember all those threads so
they we tend to pick a few which isn't
bad because then it keeps it the the
quality you you zoom kind of comes up
with that yes so like there's a couple
times where people were making points
and I would want to dive into that point
but you can't like thread off a video
conversation I have to kind of bring it
up in my thing and kind of disjointed
and far apart yeah yeah but that's you
know those the different modalities have
their different pros and cons and are
useful at different times
and so that's why when it's idea cafe
that the kind of verbal and discussion
and the stuff that are trigger things in
other people's mind is a benefit and if
you had it more structured you wouldn't
get that benefit so different modalities
for different yeah I just cuz like for
me I also like structure and the idea
cafe is a structure for a conversation
that we don't get in just open
conversation where it's a lot of small
talk it's like the fact that everyone
takes a turn and it's set out like that
I don't know how to make it more
structure besides maybe like eliminating
it to three minutes each so that there's
more open time after which is not much
structure but it's like less time
in-between hearing everyone speak and
then and playing with that right playing
with what is what does this look like as
some questions especially the life ones
like when we were doing donor conception
stories those needed more than five
minutes mental illness and how its
impacted your life and even more than
five minutes and we have it's cutting
people off and also the conversation
kind of was more than half an hour
it doesn't need to stop at half an hour
that's more again because of my vision
of like the social media platform of it
being on the half an hour's because if
it's on the hours that means there's 24
today instead of 48 which just means you
have to be starting on an hour that's
not that is a break in but it's not as
flexible for people's schedules as on
the half an hour or they just overlap
like it's like the half an hour's they
start on the half an hour but whatever
like there's so many different ways that
it doesn't need to be just because again
my like rigidity of like half an hour
we're not that's like and I imagine
we'll experiment with different ways of
doing that and you know it is their need
for some sort of digital talking stick
and doesn't need to be enforced it is it
just need to be like a symbol on each
person's screen and stuff or just you
know maybe there is a different format
where you interrupt or one person is
only allowed to ask questions right and
there's quite a few different there's
actually a website categor categorizing
different systems like and wisdom cafe
that was it was that that there was that
the original what was broken
in Ward cafes in that list although some
of them don't apply to - what - the idea
Cafe video concept but some of them will
so it'd be interesting to look through
that list and kind of try different
formulations but I'm sure that's all
something that we want to do in the
future yeah do you want to send me that
list at one point and then I'll put it
in the comments for this video as well
if you don't because me looking for that
it's gonna be a lot harder than you know
anyway like that looks like yeah yeah
I'm gonna have to find it again but so I
may not have it immediately but I'll
gonna find it yeah awesome
no because it's I mean idea Cafe is one
of infinite ways of doing it and it's
like you said adapted after the World
Cafe because because it isn't just a way
to have a four-person conversation it's
a way to have a thousand person
conversation right and rotating around
and that's was kind of the point was
like if we have a million members how
does everyone feel like their voice is
heard when we have an issue and how do
we then get the best ideas out so that a
million people don't have to listen to a
million people we don't have time for
that but everyone should be heard by
somebody and then the issues that are
brought up need to be brought to the top
and the solutions that we then talk
about for those issues need to the best
solutions need to be brought forward and
I did find the link I remembered the
participate a adat net is the website
and method 167 I'd suggest and she's
linked over the stream yard yet chat
that takes you directly to the World
Cafe link and then I don't know if they
have things like other similar or
techniques because they're so I have a
lot of techniques that won't apply at
all but yeah that'd probably be a good
place to start what's a plenty go take a
look at that I'm also like what I had
taken on last week was having the five
conversations just like this is the
first week this is the first thing that
the idea to cafe game be and that takes
more coordination than this and the
thing we we do with my brother tomorrow
the
the tech for purpose are you joining us
tomorrow I put you yeah is gonna mention
to you that my game hey work life is
getting a little stressful so I'm gonna
have to I I may not be quite as visible
so I can't I'm not making any promises
at the moment okay you're in the
description here I gave you the link
then you're also in the description for
someone joining us but don't feel
pressure to join if you don't think you
know if you're you need to play game a
we all need to put food on this right so
that's part of this right it's like well
which it was on the agenda like what
part of this is enjoyable and what part
of it makes it more enjoyable and easier
for us right if there's something simple
someone else make this that'd be great
really like um just keep that in mind
keep that as part of the conversation
right is this feeling fun is it feeling
arduous like I think it's it sounds
ridiculous but I think that's really
important that's saving the world is fun
like creating the thing that makes it so
that because it's gonna be
it doesn't even like faking fun so that
the audience likes it not the point
because it's about like the actual are
you enjoying coming to the medians right
and that doesn't mean stop coming to the
medians but like what can we create that
is is more fun right what would make it
more enjoyable and sometimes it is just
no this is getting in the way of game a
and I actually need to concentrate you
know my family's sick or whatever it
happens to be that's why it'll be great
when there's more board members or more
like people physically here because then
we don't need to feel as much pressure
to come and be part of it every week
like it moves forward without you right
when there's two of us that's a little a
little harder and say that's also
something we want to talk about is
recruit me like how to get more people
who want to do do this piece possibly
someone has a crowdfunding experience
would be awesome but yeah that's true I
think getting the
and maybe it shouldn't wait till that
far but having a recover landing page
and start getting people's email
addresses would give us the ability or
just to do calls out on this meeting and
any of the other meetings that you do
that people reach out to us if they find
these ideas interesting and want to
build on them or with them yeah yeah
sorry I was gonna say I just can't think
of any personal people that I would that
would reach out to at the moment
although you know just posting this
stuff on our social media which I know
you do and then maybe in that blurb
saying you know I guess we almost need
someplace to read to direct people well
you can just say to you know if you want
to help make the world a better place
all having fun then you know DM if it's
Twitter or whatever so yeah absolutely
there's a hard place because you kind of
have to be on it at the moment right
when someone roadies you'll see some
things but people don't like it if
people don't retweet it it disappears
nearly instantly and unless you were on
Twitter ten years ago they don't live
around 10 years ago ever unless you were
on at the beginning got 10,000
subscribers in this like community
that's ready to support you that's not
really like it's hard it's hard on
Twitter and Facebook
I was the beginning and I haven't been
because it's my friends and family and
quite frankly they don't seem to care
like they're anything but now my face
book is filled with TV people and these
people who have their own type of
projects that are more that I think now
I can I can post there more and it isn't
about necessarily reaching out to
individual people it is about like hey
who has crowdfunding who wants to come
in help make the world a better place
look what this looks like right like we
do have at least these links to showcase
what it looks like to do and a live
board meeting right it's not super
stressful
we don't have millions of people
trolling us while we're talking and you
know it's like there's something how
about building this as we go and so will
actually be somewhat more scary I would
imagine once this goes viral for
somebody to come and be part of it on
online then when there's the odd
comments that speaking at which someone
comment cuz I get that one Ernesto so
saying hi that's gonna say looking like
Ernesto who comes comes every week I
don't remember where I was but but yeah
doing so I'm definitely taking on doing
the videos I also have to let go of the
prevent like I'm never gonna be done
there's no like I I need to do 10 videos
not the thousand that I want to get to
every little knee shove every little
thing that I want to talk about which is
kind of what stops me from explaining
any of it as I wanna explain all of it
and so those four that I talked about
the essential ones and and then one on
the projects if that's kind of that
needs to happen and I can honestly I
have three of them done already so the
other two I can do this week and having
the preliminary let like not landing
page but document
even if I have other ones I haven't done
those gonna be two different documents
right I can keep adding ones from this
one to this one as they get done and
creating something that is because what
I was saying is there are a ton of
people who end up coming on board like
I'm tube or on periscope not a ton but
the odd person will be like what I tell
me what this is about this sounds
awesome and I'm like good question
like I don't have a way for them to kind
of get caught up right to be literally
come like ask me questions and that's
not I get why that's not as effective as
I was I've always known that it's not
effective it was just what was in my
capacity and now that I have the idea
for the video series I think it's a good
way to be like okay well first of all if
someone's willing to watch half an hour
of video right in five minute increments
that kind of shows they're somewhat
committed right for somebody come on
board watch 30 seconds if you like I'm
in it's like are you do you know what
we're doing
what's the and also be great to see have
you watch it and say they don't even
like there might be pieces you're like
oh I didn't know we were doing that okay
you know those I don't know if anything
so far I know you
to keep my scopes and stuff has resonate
like yeah there's also the together tech
piece which is ours right it's committed
societies and isn't mine is and then
there's me right like my life isn't a
democracy my life isn't uh like there's
my personal journey and then there's
like together tech being created and
sometimes it's hard to tease those
things apart but like my opinions on
Jordan Peterson or my opinions on
different individuals isn't together
Tech that's just me
having a space for truth and discussion
is together Tech my truth isn't together
Tech if that makes sense yeah I just
remember when he talked about less I
posted it about doing these Friday
videos in my canonical debate lab group
or building tools to save the world
through debate or making debate
effective and they said to post a link
what I was doing it I forgot to so I'm
trying to do that now am I gonna
remember what channel I put it in how
many people are in them just about like
seven or something
yeah so I think those videos are a great
way you're gonna be posting those on the
everyw and your democracy one yeah on
this the same channel these are on and
I'll be its own playlist right so it
kind of stays yeah
rather near at the top and then also
every comments sorry every description
will link back to the page to find all
of them and I just kind of figured out
how to do the end when a video ends and
it links you to other videos like oh
that's the cool all right so I can do
that so that when you're done you get
link to the next one and you also get
linked back to the playlist from the
description to say okay well this here's
where you get more information
yeah I'm glad you're linking to the
playlist in the description because so
many videos like catch one on the middle
ones in the playlist and then they don't
link back to it and there's no way in
YouTube to say that I know of to say
what lists or this video in
hmm so I can find the related videos
because the algorithm doesn't always do
it pretty well no exactly and it's funny
I have gotten more watches like it's the
irony I don't want to concentrate on my
disagreeing with other people but the
more I kind of disagree with Jordan
Peterson or do like it's like people
find me and I'm not her if acquis
disagreement I'm not gonna like that his
I'm sure I'm gonna get his supporters
trolling me a little bit but like I
don't think he would be offended by what
I'm saying like it's like you know what
I mean it's like it's truth it's it's
it's either me and just a personality
conflict which is just how life works or
it's the idea and like finding deepness
to it and like an added truth but the
more I do those on here it is that is
that in commenting on other people's
videos or how people find it but you
can't you can't when you comment on
people's videos actually mention you
have a world-changing project cuz then
it gets marked as spam
right like if you're like hey come check
out my channel no like it's the weird
YouTube's just weird hey yeah I just
have a random thought it has to go viral
and then the top add videos to a
playlist well Ernesto maybe I'll reach
out to you and you'd help me I heard how
to do that once I create that the videos
because again these videos are varied on
them I can also now add a thumbnail to
the beginning so little little things I
can do guys still don't count in it I
don't think I'll ever be able to
actually edit them if we do a crowd
funding campaign it needs to be a
professional video that explains it with
graphics and that level of stuff and so
having somebody who is able to do that
hey Liv and they were they were added
started earning your pronouns Liv she he
they hadn't said before that having um
yeah the they found me through the
Jordan Peter video response the more I
do those which I am I am called to do
those ones I did one on Charles
eisen-steen I always want to say
Einstein which is not I know the one
that isn't right but crowd
campaign video that is more professional
I have a friend coming over on Monday
that we like talked during the climate
March and she does film but I don't
think she does this kind of film I also
have like Friday dinners of somebody who
does film but again not this kind of
film like they're in like film film you
know like Hollywood type phone not
crowdfunding you're not short techie
ones that have have but like they might
know someone
and I again don't know how much they're
willing to do it for free she thanks
like I was gonna guess she because it's
lives but yeah he's still going to
assume I usually go with BAE and so I
mean otherwise they're just makes little
sense but I'm just going to back to the
agenda that I wrote down things on so
the marketing to introverts I just want
to tell you like so on when's
Wednesday's yeah cuz Tuesday's is the
idea Cafe Wednesday's there's a few
groupie people that are meeting to do be
a make a rule practice mm-hm it's me and
like for other people and so we had our
first one this week it was really cool
part of which came up was one of the
persons shared how she kind of does the
macro practicing of maker rules like
meditation and like internal looking at
emotions and going under them and we
have very similar like we go to health
conditions that a lot of chronic health
conditions are tied to emotions and
thoughts and that kind of thing and so
she's been working on getting healthier
and doing that and then Janelle share
that she's an extrovert and that she
does the opposite she goes outward when
she does it she kind of like feels the
room and the weird thing is like I
there's only five of us there but I
would say I'm more of an introvert and I
was tied to the introvert and there was
another extrovert there who's like yes I
also do that piece and the bigger piece
was the extroverts for like yes there's
something online when we do video
conversation that is missing but isn't
there when you're in the real world
right they can you can't feel the energy
you can't play off of that me and the
other introvert we're like no we prefer
this because there isn't so much energy
coming at us right there isn't so much
information that we can actually be more
ourselves and get more out of a video
chat and there was a
piece of that where I was like sorry I
must have for you nesters clobberin sure
my story that I was like oh the idea of
Caffe is even more powerful for
introverts than it is for extroverts and
yet I don't know how to get them to see
that besides experiencing it not like I
don't think we're gonna solve that but I
just wanted to bring that into it yeah
one thing might be interesting is on
another episode interview an interview
interview introvert and then may put
that in the title just to see so they
can kind of share the experience like
they aren't introverts yeah what the
question would be but yeah that's how do
we do this for introverts everyone can
share for five minutes I think how how
would you know how yeah I think that'd
be good but I mean also just if if you
if we do know an introvert that finds it
and I go oh that's interesting just to
do one of your separate videos just
talking about what was it like and
putting that out with introvert in the
title I think but also doing an idea
cafe on or just for the idea cafe maybe
choose a title that would be interesting
to introverts as well so those three
ideas I think are all equally yeah and
I'm just wondering it well I was saying
that there Ernesto had mentioned that uh
he might be able to help with the video
and that is what he does for limit a
living but he has limited free time
totally both understandable and I also
love but there are three people watching
and one of those three people is exactly
what we need for crowdsourcing even if
we can't yet pay him and can't fully
utilize it right like even if he was
able to do an hour to a free work a week
and it was ten hours of time and it took
five weeks that's better than nothing
I read like that's amazingly better than
nothing and it's amazingly better than
what I'm capable of doing and I'm not
looking for someone to do that on all of
my videos because that's a lot of work
right until I had there's enough
viewership until there's money coming in
from YouTube to pay for those things it
doesn't make sense for someone to commit
to that but doing a video right
like one crowdsourcing video oh sorry
one crowdfunding video this
crowd-sourced that is learning with a
complete transparency i.e you get credit
for it like that somebody came on board
and did this is I think that's kind of
what's happening with the person doing
the website it's time to talk her I was
like yes mention that you did it on one
of the pages I think that is important
that like to link back to your portfolio
and to do right to do that piece because
it is it's the least we can do and it's
the power of creating something with
cooperation is that people want to
cooperate even if they don't have the
capacity right like we only have so many
hours in the day and the more we're
capable of giving people more time by
making game a less important in your
life right because people to find food
other places are able to find connection
and like just resources other places the
more people will be willing to step into
more labor for the collective without
ever requiring anybody give something
like it's a voluntary piece including I
can't afford to do this unless I'm
getting paid for it right right and
honoree not to now someone's like give
me a million oh if someone was like you
know I what you said would cost ten
thousand I could do for a thousand um
well if it's usable sure if it's not you
don't it mean like finding I don't know
just open and transparency and finding
out what works so we still don't have a
thousand dollars to put into it right so
like where do we get that from then but
like this is with three people watching
having a hundred people watching in
every you know I have a thousand dollars
I got money on Bitcoin I'm willing to
check that in right like those things
absolutely will happen they just don't
happen at to three people and yet they
do like the amount of times this has
happened I this story struck with like a
labor platform and how we like figure
things out in society with labor like
well I don't know like I know there's
some tasks nobody's gonna like to do
like cleaning the washroom and this
person I would the first person I said
that to it was like I like clean
washrooms it's like seriously like
that's the one thing I was like no one's
gonna want to do that and the issue is
we don't think anybody want
to do the work either we can't do or
don't want to do and for every piece of
work there's somebody who both can and
wants to do it it's just do they have
the capacity yeah there might be there
might be a mismatch between the supply
and the demand absolutely but yeah but
the you know finding little incentives I
mean you know our goal is to not be
rivalry it's not necessarily that
there's no incentives in the system
right there's no form of money or
anything so yeah I think I think giving
people the freedom to work on the things
that they're passionate about will solve
a huge portion of the needs and then
what little bit we need you know every
once in a while I need a job that like
washing the dishes and you know sweeping
and stuff like that I can put something
on and I can think in the back of my
mind so you need some monotonous tasks
that that yeah I think that we will find
a way to match that kind of that need
those needs up with people absolutely I
think that's just a platform and the
more it's created for everybody not just
for our needs right it's like hey a
charity can come and put what they need
on and people can find spaces to do
things that they feel good about means
using their skills that is something
that's very needed in society
and especially if you're like what's a
nice five minutes here right or you're
like hey I can input some crowdsourcing
when I'm at the supermarket right
someone needs to know the price of this
or we all need to know the price of this
I can do two quick tasks so supermarket
and feel like I contributed like the
easier we make it and then the more we
make people's but anyone could input an
information the supermarket you need to
have the ability to do video to be able
to step up and do video right or be
willing to learn that and so those are
different but having one platform that
enables the individual to say what they
can and want to do and then like you
said like a few there's dishes to be
done and you want to do menial you know
menial is probably the wrong word but
like easy tasks that it's just like you
don't need to think you just do it
you can sign up for that right see who
in your neighborhood needs that done you
feel good about it cuz they're not doing
it for probably a multi-millionaire you
were doing it for like a a senior who
can't do that anymore or a new mom just
like can't be bothered right now you
know those kind of yeah that's kind of
thing so huh so that I had mentioned the
introvert thing and I would love we
talked about that so thank you and then
we already talked about the other thing
too which was um well that we didn't
actually I just mentioned that we could
talk about it is there is this enjoyable
for for you cuz it's kind of designed by
my enjoyment like I'm like I can show up
for an hour and have a conversation and
it should be it should be created for
everyone's enjoyment right but like
mm-hmm
the certain degree whoever's on board
has to kind of match with the first like
if we find this enjoyable the third
person needs to figure out how to me if
it's not enjoyable maybe find something
else to do right now button right right
yeah I yeah I find it interesting my my
interests yeah I don't I don't know if I
specifically enjoy the talking on video
and in this specific part of it but it
allows me to exercise my brain and then
it gives me things to benefit so it's
not unenjoyable or it's not you know but
yeah yeah I'm not sure if it was just
come and talking a chat with someone
around you know I yeah
so I don't question the over overall the
process is enjoyable yeah
and part of kind of saying I'm not sure
I can make the Saturday and you know
having things makes it more enjoyable
because I don't have that kind of stress
not the point to commit I'm hoping you
know in another six months or so I can I
have a little bit more time to commit to
things yeah I think that's important
just one that I'm open to actually
hearing answers
questions instead of just like talking
about like I answered it for you it's
enjoyable what do you mean and like this
wasn't enjoyable for me either being on
live on video but I think there's a real
importance to it both that its
transparency right it's like what
starting the thing that can be here in
after our first few projects right from
date from day one and it's the ability
for like arnesto and live to watch and
say hey I have that and come on board
and be on video or contribute in the
comments it's the way for it to go viral
it's a way for us to get crowdfunding
and crowdsourcing and so there's a lot
of benefit to it even if yes as
introverts being live on video comes
with a certain amount of vulnerability
and that can be scary and owning that
especially the more people we get there
that are watching it that's where again
I think that getting in on this point is
really it's a lot easier doing this with
three people then a dozen people there
was a time where I would go live on
YouTube I was going live on periscope
and I'd have one maybe three people
watching and that was fine because
periscopes just a different feeling but
when I'm to go live on YouTube and I'd
get a V where I was like I gotta go
looks like because I would just go I
would go live to record and then someone
would come on board and I'd be like
mm-hm
that was not me this was supposed to
happen but like owning that and like
allowing myself to grow incrementally
into it not push myself has now I'm like
if the number could go to a million and
I'm gonna sit here and and talk through
it I'm maybe going to ignore the
comments because that would be way too
much feedback but it's a it's important
to know like what like this has to be
for introverts and extroverts it can't
just be for people who want to be want
to be on the screen because honestly the
people who want power and want to be on
screen or probably the last people we
want actually being in power and
actually be it on screen so therefore
people who don't want to kind of have to
step up and do it which is the position
I've put myself in and I am actually
kind of enjoying it now that I'm here if
that makes sense yeah give me a half
idea an app to volunteer to pick up
groceries for people yes exactly
I'd love that sorry Levi I don't know
what you meant by what that's a good
word because I don't know what I said
it's from kabuna memory that I said so
many words but well do we want to take
on things for next week yeah
so if the if the lady doing the website
reaches out to me I'll certainly
coordinate with her and see if there's a
way I can contribute to it without
interrupting her flow and then that's
probably the main thing I think that's
the main thing I don't think there was
anything else I'm committing to and
that's also a big piece of this it's
like honestly this is what we're
committing to is being here for this
hour and working doing stuff not
necessarily taking on stuff in-between
time but it's also only an hour so it's
nice if we if we can and I'm taking on
doing the other two videos in the in the
five video series there will be many
more videos but doing those five the
tech is powerful tech is risky which
I've already done
check together is less risky which have
also already done and then checked
together is more powerful which I'm
going to do today and then the handful
of tools that we need to kind of open up
collaboration on a massive scale that is
like big tools we need for together tech
itself and even another video of like
been what we can create with those and I
think that foundation and then I can add
on to that like what does it mean to be
democratic to be transparent
what benefit that gives us to
out-compete Facebook like there's a
there's a real not just because it feels
good because it's you know left-leaning
it's like there's an actually real
tangible reason and
benefit that it gives us as a collective
and so yes so doing those videos and
then continuing the five conversations
that I have lined up you never know have
you already created a playlist for those
I did like in a Google Doc I kind of
wrote out a few of them and linking but
you don't have a a playlist on YouTube
yet for that group right not yeah I have
I have three of them uploaded on on
YouTube at their own private because I'm
going to make them go live a lot like
the idea was to start on December 1st
but if I'm done by next Friday and they
can start next Friday the idea is just
to kind of do one a day for however many
days that they they're up and then it's
good link to him for her and at the same
time like 9 a.m. every day just not my
starting point when I put videos up but
like I feel I want to so I'm doing one
which works for me right not for the
algorithm no but we don't want to be a
slave to the algorithm no no we want to
create our own algorithms that are slave
to us it's how blessed free of life and
humanity and community and all that good
stuff all right so I don't think we have
to like stay on here until no and we get
out and all your we hit all your topics
I didn't even pull up the agenda I just
let yeah it's just the same what we did
the introvert marketing and then is this
enjoyable is there a way to make it more
enjoyable and then filling in the
conversation as we go and so um yeah I
think we're good if I see you tomorrow
for the tech the purpose goal-setting
group great if not don't feel the need
kind of get sleep take care of yourself
and I will see you next Friday and I
will see everyone else in the in-between
time when I pop on for when I feel like
it yeah alright bye YouTube